<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C on Karthikey Kadati</title>
    <link>https://karthikey1.github.io/my-cv/tags/c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C on Karthikey Kadati</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://karthikey1.github.io/my-cv/tags/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Scheduler: Validating FMLP for GSoC 2026 (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://karthikey1.github.io/my-cv/posts/fmlp-rtems-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://karthikey1.github.io/my-cv/posts/fmlp-rtems-validation/</guid>
      <description>In the last post, I talked about how I modernized the FMLP implementation. But writing the code is only half the battle. Maintainers like Gedare Bloom and Joel Sherrill demanded proof that my changes didn&amp;rsquo;t break the math.&#xA;Validation Strategy: Beyond &amp;ldquo;It Works&amp;rdquo; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just run a &amp;ldquo;happy path&amp;rdquo; test. I had to build a suite that actively tried to break the scheduler.&#xA;spfmlp01: Validates the Long (suspension) variant. spfmlp02: Validates the Short (busy-wait) variant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Kernel: Architecting FMLP for RTEMS 7</title>
      <link>https://karthikey1.github.io/my-cv/posts/fmlp-rtems-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://karthikey1.github.io/my-cv/posts/fmlp-rtems-implementation/</guid>
      <description>The goal was clear: Introduce the Flexible Multiprocessor Locking Protocol (FMLP) into the RTEMS 7 SMP SuperCore. But bridging the gap between a 2020 research patch and a 2026 production kernel required a massive architectural overhaul.&#xA;The SuperCore Logic I had to introduce two new control structures into cpukit/score:&#xA;FMLPS_Control: Manages the metadata for the Short (busy-wait) variant. FMLPL_Control: Manages the state for the Long (suspension) variant. Unlike the research code which used ad-hoc locking, I aligned everything with the modern Thread_queue_Context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing a Race Condition in the rtl8723bs Driver</title>
      <link>https://karthikey1.github.io/my-cv/posts/linux-kernel-rtl8723bs-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://karthikey1.github.io/my-cv/posts/linux-kernel-rtl8723bs-fix/</guid>
      <description>I was digging through the drivers/staging/rtl8723bs code when I spotted something off in the packet transmission path.&#xA;The function update_attrib updates two critical things for a network station: security info and physical layer attributes. But looking at the code, these updates were happening completely unprotected.&#xA;/* Before Fix */ if (update_attrib_sec_info(padapter, pattrib, psta) == _FAIL) { res = _FAIL; goto exit; } // &amp;lt;--- A lot can happen here in an SMP system update_attrib_phy_info(padapter, pattrib, psta); pattrib-&amp;gt;psta = psta; In a multi-core system, if another thread tries to read the station state right in the middle of this, it gets garbage data.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
